Richard Ghrist II

Cleveland, OH | 330.993.0105 <u>rickyghrist.com</u> ricky.ghrist@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Software Engineer and Application Developer with 4+ years of experience in full stack technologies while practicing SCRUM. I am focused on developing meaningful and correct solutions, improving agile methods and mentoring. My most experienced languages are python, .net, t-sql, react.js, typescript and docker.

EXPERIENCE

OnShift, Cleveland, OH

May 2019 - Present

Software Developer

Supported legacy python applications and worked on the .net rewrite of those projects. Worked directly with VP's of customer success to ensure customer satisfaction. Enhanced our docker structure in Azure AKS.

- Team lead of 7 for the .net core rewrite of an existing python legacy application
- Tech lead for the existing python engagement application
- Laid groundwork for the Auth0 implementation to replace our homegrown SSO solution
- Worked with Ops to use the Releases in Azure DevOps to replace our Jenkins and Ansible usage by 75%
- Team/Tech lead of 6 for the Time and Attendance project in MongoDb, React and .Net
- Successfully architected and implemented database designs, service bus usage, and azure function usage across the product floor

OnShift, Cleveland, OH

Dec 2018 - May 2019

Associate Software Developer

Engagement web application that used python, react, postgres, AWS and made use of a micro service architecture with Kubernetes.

- Refactored the backend python code to improve our database call throughput by 30%
- Standardized React patterns being used (ver 15.x) and the usage of LaunchDarkly for new features
- Used AWS to manage our Kubernetes cluster, kinesis steams and Cloudwatch jobs
- Proposed RFC's and diagrams on our architecture which led to a .net core rewrite of the backend
- Used daily SCRUM practices and released every one to two weeks

TekSystems – National General Insurance, Independence, OH Software Developer I

May 2018 – Dec 2018

Renewals team that worked in C#, VB.Net, git and VSTS. Worked on a constant stream of issues generated on the business side with high priority deadlines. Implemented agile methods that resulted in higher team productivity.

- Worked in a waterfall shop with hard releases of every two weeks
- Implemented SOLID in our project that created a simpler code base with broken out dependencies
- Lead a unit test project that in two months, we went from 0% coverage to 45% of our system

MRI Software, Solon, OH

Mar 2017 – May 2018

Software Developer I

Educated and mentor 6-7 new hires monthly through technical skills classes including SOLID, OOP, and custom tooling.

- Reworked the entire renewal system for residential owning clients in the UK
- Minimized expenditures and wait times by completing bulk renewals two weeks ahead of time allowing the extra time to be used to remove 15% of client-reported defects in other areas of the program

EDUCATION

Kent State University, B.A Computer Science The Ohio State University, B.A Psychology May 2015 - May 2017 Aug 2010 - Dec 2014